A Finding Aid to the Livingston L. Biddle, Jr. Papers, Circa 1940-2002, in the Archives of American Art
Archives of American Art
- Writings, circa 1940-2000; Series 4; Archival Resource Key; 12 Linear feet Boxes 6-18
  - Short Stories, Archival Resource Key (Box 16)
    - "Road to Mandalay", circa 1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Songs, circa 1970-2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Speech Notes, circa 1970-2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 5-14)
  - Speech Notes, Art in Architecture Program, 1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - Speech Notes, "Government and the Arts," Princeton Library in New York, 1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - Untitled Manuscripts, circa 1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 17-20)
  - Untitled Manuscripts, circa 1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 1-14)
  - By Others, Archival Resource Key (Box 18)
    - "Art/Work/USA" by Barbara Rose, 1981; Archival Resource Key; 1 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Articles by Claiborne Pell, 1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Biography of Claiborne Pell by Unknown Author, 1991; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Bocto, Musical Script by Hugh Wheeler, 1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - "The Eagle," Film Introduction by Unknown Author, circa 1985; Archival Resource Key; 1 Sound cassette (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - "Political and Policy Change in the Arts," American Council for the Arts Seminar Papers by Various Authors, 1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - "Saving the Railroads," The Commonweal by Claiborne Pell, 1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Speeches by Claiborne Pell, 1963-1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Statements on Joan Mondale by Claiborne Pell, 1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - "Suggested Background Materials, 1780-1965, for Speech in Support of Government Involvement in Arts..." by Robert A. Rickard, 1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - The Widow Claire, Script by Horton Foote, 1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 11)
- National Endowment for the Arts, 1964-2000; Series 5; Archival Resource Key; 10 Linear feet Boxes 18-27, 42
  This series documents Biddle's lengthy involvement with the NEA from its creation in 1965 through his appointments as congressional liaison officer, deputy chairman, and his appointment by President Jimmy Carter as chairman from 1977 to 1981. Included are drafts by Biddle for the National Foundation of the Arts and Humanities Act of 1965 which led to the creation of the NEA and the National Endowment for the Humanities, files for agencies that worked closely with the NEA, conferences and events, briefing books that detail Biddle's travel agendas and provide background information on the arts of each locality, financial information, programs managed by the NEA, and reports. Additionally, three video recordings and one sound reel titled "Swearing-In of L.L. Biddle, Jr." are included.
  - General, circa 1970-2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 12-18)
    Oversized material housed in Box 42.
  - Agencies, Archival Resource Key (Box 18)
    - American Arts Alliance, 1991; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 19)
    - Association of Art Museum Directors, Meeting Agendas, 1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 20-21)
    - Cleveland Area Arts Council, 1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 22)
  - Agencies, Archival Resource Key (Box 19)
    - Center for Southern Folklore, 1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Institute of Museum Services, Meeting Agenda, 1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - National Assembly of State Art Agencies, Meeting Agenda, 1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - National Council on the Arts, General, 1965-2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 4-5)
    - National Council on the Arts, Meeting Agendas, 1978-1981; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 6-11)
    - National Endowment for the Humanities, 1976-1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 12)
    - Public Interest Groups, 1978-1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 13)
    - National Governor's Association, Meeting Agenda, 1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 14-15)
    - State Arts, 1964-1988; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 16-18)
  - Agencies, Archival Resource Key (Box 20)
    - State Arts, 1964-1988; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 1-3)
  - Appointment as Chairman, 1965-1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 4-7)
  - Appointment as Chairman, 1965-1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Appointment as Chairman, Nomination, 1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Appointment as Chairman, Statement of Initiatives, 1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Appointment as Chairman, "Swearing-In of L.L. Biddle, Jr.", 1977; Archival Resource Key; 1 Sound tape reel (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Appointment as Congressional Liaison Officer, 1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Briefing Books, 1977-1995; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 12-25)
  - Briefing Books, 1977-1995; Archival Resource Key (Box 21, Folder 1-21)
  - Briefing Books, 1977-1995; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Folder 1-21)
  - Briefing Books, 1977-1995; Archival Resource Key (Box 23, Folder 1-8)
  - Committee, Policy and Planning, 1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - Committee, Presidential Task Force on Arts and Humanities, 1979-1981; Archival Resource Key (Box 23, Folder 10-11)
  - Committee, Special Counsel for Arts and Education, 1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - Committee, Task Force on Community Arts, 1978-1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 23, Folder 13)
  - Committee, Visual and Design Arts Planning Communities, 1985-1987; Archival Resource Key (Box 23, Folder 14)
  - Conference, "America's Creative Legacy: An NEA Forum at Harvard," Panelist, 1989-2000; Archival Resource Key; 2 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 23, Folder 15-17)
  - Conference, Bucks County Conservancy, 1979-1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 23, Folder 18)
  - Conference, "Convocation on the Arts in Education," Speaker, 1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 23, Folder 19)
  - Event, American Society of Landscape Architects, Awards Ceremony Presenter, 1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 23, Folder 20)
  - Event, Corcoran Gallery of Art, Codex Leicester Exhibition Speaker, 1981; Archival Resource Key (Box 23, Folder 21)
  - Event, Democratic National Committee, Arts Plank Presentation, 1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 23, Folder 22)
  - Event, Foundation for the Joffrey Ballet, Inc., Speaker, 1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Event, Guest Lists, 1979-1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Event, Lyric Opera of Chicago, Performance Honoring Biddle, 1981; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Event, Ohio Theatre Golden Jubilee Gala, 1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Event, United States Cultural Delegation to China, 1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Financial, Annual Reports, 1984-1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 6-7)
  - Financial, Appropriations Requests, 1979-1984; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 8-19)
  - Financial, Bell System American Orchestra's Project Funding, 1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 1-2)
  - Financial, Budget, 1981; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Financial, Budget Restructuring, 1981; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Financial, Budget Requests, 1981-1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 5-8)
  - Legislation, Helms Amendment, circa 1989; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 9-10)
  - Legislation, National Foundation on the Arts and Humanities Act of 1965, 1964-1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 11-13)
  - Press Coverage, Clippings, 1979-1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 14-18)
  - Press Coverage, New York Times, circa 1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 19)
  - Programs, Archival Resource Key (Box 26)
    - Arts in Education Programs, 1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 26, Folder 1-2)
    - Businesses Supporting the Arts, 1978-1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - Challenge Grant Program, 1978-1984; Archival Resource Key (Box 26, Folder 4-5)
    - Fellowships, 1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - International Advancement, 1978-1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 26, Folder 7-9)
    - Jazz Programs, 1977-1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 26, Folder 10)
    - Minority Endowment Recipient Activities, 1978-1981; Archival Resource Key (Box 26, Folder 11-13)
    - National Arts Week Proclamation, 1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 26, Folder 14)
    - Presidential Medal of Excellence in the Arts, 1978-1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 26, Folder 15)
    - Small Business Administration, Artist Business Skills, 1979-1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 26, Folder 16)
    - Veteran's Administration, Artist-In-Residence, 1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 26, Folder 17)
  - Report, "The Arts in America," Report to the President and Congress, 1992; Archival Resource Key (Box 26, Folder 18)
  - Report, "The Arts in America," Film, 1992; Archival Resource Key; 1 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 26, Folder 19)
  - Report, House Appropriations Committee, Investigative Report on NEA, 1978-1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 26, Folder 20-21)
  - Report, House Appropriations Committee, Investigative Report on NEA, 1978-1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 27, Folder 1-2)
  - Report, Independent Commission Report to Congress, 1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Report, Independent Commission, Written Testimony by Biddle, 1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Report, "Unity.... Quality.... Access" by Biddle, circa 1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Oversized General from Box 18, Folders 12-18, 1970-1998; circa 1970-2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 42)
- Committee and Political Campaign Files, 1944-2001; Series 6; Archival Resource Key; 3.5 Linear feet Boxes 27-30
  This series is arranged as 2 subseries.
  Missing Title
  6.1: Committees, 1944-2001
  6.2: Political Campaigns, 1964-1994
  This series consists of files, primarily accumulated after Biddle's NEA chairmanship, documenting his service as a prominent fundraiser and organizer for multiple committees and political campaigns. The files contain correspondence, meeting agendas and notes, solicitation letter drafts, and printed material for the American Council for the Arts, American Field Service Committee, Committee on Labor and Public Welfare, Corcoran Museum Board of Overseers Exhibitions Committee, Cosmos Club Arts Committee, Duke Ellington School of the Arts, Kennedy Center for the Performing Arts, National Museum of Women in the Arts, various Washington, D.C. arts organizations, and the Catherine Bertini, Jimmy Carter, Judy Hancock, Walter Mondale, Claiborne Pell, and Sidney Yates campaigns. This series includes one sound recording.
  - Committees, 1944-2001; 6.1; Archival Resource Key
    - The Actor's Studio, Trustee Group Chairman, 1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 27, Folder 6-7)
    - American Association of Museums, 1984; Archival Resource Key (Box 27, Folder 8)
    - American Council for the Arts, Advocacy Day, 1988-1991; Archival Resource Key (Box 27, Folder 9-10)
    - American Council for the Arts, "Connections: The Arts in a Changing Society" Conference, 1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 27, Folder 11)
    - American Field Service Committee, 1944-1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 27, Folder 12-20)
    - American Field Service Committee, 1944-1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 1-3)
    - Arena Stage, Benefit Gala, 1982-1984; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - Arts United Fund Campaign, 1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 5-6)
    - Association of American University Presses, Inc., 1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 7-8)
    - Charity Farm, Chairman, 1997-1999; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 9-10)
    - Chopin Foundation, Board of Directors, 1984; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 11)
    - Choruses of the World, Board Member, 1984; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 12)
    - The City Tavern Club, 2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 13)
    - Committee on Labor and Public Welfare, 1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 14)
    - Congressional Subcommittee on Education, Arts, and Humanities, 1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 15-16)
    - Connecticut College, Visiting Committee, 1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 17)
    - Corcoran Museum Board of Overseers Exhibitions Committee Meeting, 1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 18)
    - Cosmos Club, Arts Committee, 1988-2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 19-20)
    - Council of AFL-CIO Unions for Scientific, Professional, and Cultural Employees, 1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 21)
    - The Council of the Phillips Collection, 1992; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 22)
    - The Duke Ellington School of the Arts, Search Committee, 1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 23)
    - Fondo del Sol Visual Arts and Media Center, 1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 24-25)
    - Ford's Theatre, Advisory Committee, 1984; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 26)
    - Friends of the Nancy Hanks Center, Inc., Board of Directors, 1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - The Fund for Arts and Culture of Central and Eastern Europe, Board of Advisors, 1991; Archival Resource Key (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - Kennedy Center for the Performing Arts, Golden Circle Member, 1973-1995; Archival Resource Key (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - National Foundation for Cancer Research, Advisory Committee for Designated Research Gifts and Endowment, 1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - National Humanities Alliance, 1990-1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 29, Folder 5)
    - National Museum of Women in the Arts, Board, 1977-2002; Archival Resource Key (Box 29, Folder 6-8)
    - National Music Theater Network, Advisory Council Chairman, 1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 29, Folder 9)
    - National Symphony Orchestra Association, Board of Directors, 1981-1984; Archival Resource Key (Box 29, Folder 10)
    - Pacific Symphony Orchestra, Honorary Committee, 1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 29, Folder 11)
    - Paul Hill Chorale, Benefit Chairman, 1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 29, Folder 12)
    - Senate Special Subcommittee on Arts and Humanities, 1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 29, Folder 13)
    - Senate Subcommittee on the Smithsonian Institution, Hall of Historic Americans, 1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 29, Folder 14)
    - Southern Alleghenies Museum of Art Schwab Gala, Honorary Chairman, 1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 29, Folder 15)
    - Washington, D.C. Arts Partnerships, 1981-1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 29, Folder 16)
    - The Washington Ballet, 1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 29, Folder 17)
    - The Washington Chorus, 1997-2001; Archival Resource Key (Box 29, Folder 18-19)
    - The Washington Opera, Board of Trustees, 1991-2001; Archival Resource Key (Box 29, Folder 20-21)
    - Washington Performing Arts Society, 1979-1989; Archival Resource Key; Includes 1 sound cassette (Box 29, Folder 22-23)
  - Political Campaigns, 1964-1994; 6.2; Archival Resource Key
    - Catherine Bertini for Congress Campaign, 1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 29, Folder 24-29)
    - Claiborne Pell Campaigns, 1964-1984; Archival Resource Key (Box 29, Folder 30-34)
    - Jimmy Carter/Walter Mondale Campaign, 1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 30, Folder 1-2)
    - Judy Hancock for Congress Campaign, 1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 30, Folder 3)
    - Sidney Yates for Congress Committee, 1984-1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 30, Folder 4-7)
    - Walter Mondale Campaign, Artists for Mondale, 1981-1984; Archival Resource Key (Box 30, Folder 8-13)
- Personal Legal Records, 1952-1986; Series 7; Archival Resource Key; 1 Linear foot Boxes 30-31
  Found in this series are estate records for Biddle's mother, Eugenia Law Biddle, and his first wife, Frances Fenton Biddle; records for an investment partnership agreement facilitated by Michael T. Yao; real estate deeds, appraisal reports, and property agreements for multiple properties; and versions of Biddle's will.
  - Estate of Eugenia Law Biddle, 1953-1984; Archival Resource Key (Box 30, Folder 14-17)
  - Estate of Frances Fenton Biddle, 1975-1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 30, Folder 18)
  - Investment Partnership Agreement, 1979-1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 30, Folder 19-20)
  - Real Estate, 1952-1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 30, Folder 21-22)
  - Real Estate, 1952-1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 31, Folder 1-7)
  - Will, 1959-1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 31, Folder 8)
- Printed Materials, circa 1950-2000; Series 8; Archival Resource Key; 3 Linear feet Boxes 31-34, 41, OV 44
  Booklets, clippings, event invitations and programs, flyers, magazines and journals, newsletters, one sound cassette of National Public Radio's program Performance Today, and posters autographed by artists Jacob Lawrence and Fritz Scholder, and astronaut John Glenn are found in this series.
  - Booklets, circa 1970-2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 31, Folder 9-13)
  - Clippings, circa 1950-2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 31, Folder 14-16)
  - Clippings, circa 1950-2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 32, Folder 1-12)
  - Event Invitations, 1970-1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 32, Folder 13-15)
  - Event Invitations, 1970-1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - Event Programs, circa 1960-2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 33, Folder 2-12)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, circa 1960-2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 33, Folder 13-15)
  - Flyers, circa 1960-2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 33, Folder 16)
  - Magazines and Journals, circa 1960-2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 33, Folder 17-19)
  - Magazines and Journals, circa 1960-2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 34, Folder 1-8)
  - Newsletters, circa 1960-2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 34, Folder 9-10)
  - "Performance Today," National Public Radio, 1986; Archival Resource Key; 1 Sound cassette (Box 34, Folder 11)
  - Posters, circa 1960-2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 34, Folder 12)
    Oversized material housed in OV 44.
  - Press Releases, circa 1960-2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 34, Folder 13)
  - Oversized Clippings from Box 31, Folders 14-16, circa 1950-2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 41)
  - Oversized Posters from Box 34, Folder 12, circa 1960-2000; Archival Resource Key (Box OV 44)
- Scrapbooks, 1970-1998; Series 9; Archival Resource Key; 0.3 Linear feet Box 34, 42
  Two scrapbooks and loose scrapbook material with memorabilia from the NEA and Biddle's travels are in this series.
  - Loose Material, 1970-1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 34, Folder 14-15)
  - Scrapbook 1, 1970-1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 42)
  - Scrapbook 2, 1970-1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 42)
- Photographs and Video Recordings, circa 1950-2002; Series 10; Archival Resource Key; 4.6 Linear feet Boxes 34-40, 42, OV 44
  Photographs are of Biddle, his family, friends and colleagues at arts and political events, and of international travel to China, Tibet, Turkey, and many other places in the United States, Europe, Asia, and Africa. The series also includes six video recordings of Biddle's trip to Russia, his hometown of Bryn Mawr, and his ancestor, St. Katherine Drexel.
  - Of Biddle, circa 1950-2002; Archival Resource Key (Box 34, Folder 16)
  - Family, circa 1950-2002; Archival Resource Key (Box 34, Folder 17)
  - Family, Hooper Home Movies of Bryn Mawr, Pennsylvania, circa 1950-2002; Archival Resource Key; 2 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 34, Folder 18)
  - Family, St. Katherine Drexel, circa 1950-2002; Archival Resource Key; 3 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 34, Folder 19)
  - Colleagues and Friends, circa 1950-2002; Archival Resource Key; Includes 3 video cassettes (Box 35, Folder 1-15)
    Oversized material housed in Box 42 and OV 44.
  - Travel, circa 1950-2002; Archival Resource Key; 1 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 35, Folder 16-18)
  - Travel, circa 1950-2002; Archival Resource Key (Box 36, Folder 1-14)
  - Travel, circa 1950-2002; Archival Resource Key (Box 37, Folder 1-13)
  - Travel, circa 1950-2002; Archival Resource Key (Box 38, Folder 1-14)
  - Travel, circa 1950-2002; Archival Resource Key (Box 39, Folder 1-16)
  - Travel, circa 1950-2002; Archival Resource Key (Box 40, Folder 1-5)
  - "American Paintings from the Armand Hammer Collection: An Inaugural Celebration," Event at National Gallery of Art, 1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 40, Folder 6)
  - Oversized Photographs of Biddle from Box 34, Folder 16, circa 1950-2002; Archival Resource Key (Box 42)
  - Oversized Colleagues and Friends from Box 35, Folders 1-15, circa 1950-2002; Archival Resource Key (Box 42)
  - Oversized Colleagues and Friends from Box 35, Folders 1-15, circa 1950-2002; Archival Resource Key (Box OV 44)
- Artwork, 1976-1989; Series 11; Archival Resource Key; 0.3 Linear feet Box 40, OV 44
  An ink drawing of singer Diahann Carroll, sketches by Ruth Asawa Lanier, watercolors by Barb Maxwell and Howard N. Watson, a cartoon by Pat Oliphant, and a silkscreen by James Rosenquist are in artwork.
  - Lanier, Ruth Asawa, Pencil Sketches of Biddle, 1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 40, Folder 6)
  - Maxwell, Barb, Watercolor of the Biddles, circa 1980s; Archival Resource Key (Box 40, Folder 7)
  - Oliphant, Pat, Cartoon, 1981; Archival Resource Key (Box OV 44)
  - Rosenquist, James, Silkscreen, 1976; Archival Resource Key (Box OV 44)
  - Watson, Howard N., Watercolor Print of White House, 1981; Archival Resource Key (Box OV 44)
  - Unknown Artist, Ink Drawing of Diahann Carroll, 1984; Archival Resource Key (Box 40, Folder 8)